# **Dwight Smith**

New York, NY (216) 835-0847 <u>dwightsmth@gmail.com</u> linkedin.com/in/elismth|zeroOrder.com

## **Summary**

Software developer with 5 years of experience building scalable, enterprise level applications used by millions of customers worldwide. With a focus on the design and implementation of large scale systems built with modern front-end technologies including TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Nodejs, HTML5 and CSS3/SCSS. Enthusiastic team player who works collaboratively across teams to deliver quality software in an agile environment.

## **Experience**

Gogotech, New York, NY - Software Developer

August 2017 - October 2022

- Launched core features for high traffic website using React.js, TypeScript and other front-end technologies while providing code reviews, QA testing and deployment support across transnational teams
- Performed critical front-end optimizations for proprietary single-page application through bug fixes and refactorings in addition to employed best practices such as file compression, CDN usage and caching
- Built and maintained RESTful API services with C# and .Net Core, utilizing various design patterns and techniques
- Developed automated end-to-end testing suite for our client-side application using Selenium framework, ultimately improving team productivity largely through the reduction of newly reported bugs in production

#### Focus Camera, Brooklyn, NY - Ecommerce Manager

January 2014 - August 2017

- Produced and managed online content for various e-commerce platforms by providing HTML and CSS support
- Collaborated closely with software developers and designers to curate and deliver quality experiences for end-users
- Analyzed sales data and related metrics to assist in the development of marketing campaign strategies

### **G2G Consulting, Washington D.C.** - Government Affairs Mediator

July 2012 - October 2013

- Authored governmental policy research for senior legislative personnel and published reports on analytical insights
- Coordinated meetings with congressional officials and contributed valuable dialog on behalf of several public entities
- Provided client management services in addition to technical support and other office related duties

## **Skills**

JavaScript | TypeScript | React.js | Node.js | C# | .Net Core | OOP | Express.js | SQL | NoSQL | Next.js | Python | Git

## **Education**

Cleveland State University, Cleveland, OH - Bachelor's of Science, Environmental Studies